

Manon Fouquet,

FULLSTACK DEVELOPPER, PROJECT MANAGER

06 41 69 70 83

ms.manonfouquet@gmail.com



LinkedIn in







Summary



I have worked as a developper and project manager for 6 years, on complex projects related to numerical optimization. I have developped or supervized the development of many large scale industrial codes, such as market clearing algorithms for the energy sector in Europe and optimization models of energy systems. I am enthusiastic and well organized in my work. I love to constantly learn new techniques and to apply them. I am now seeking a data scientist or fullstack developper job, ideally on topics with a positive impact on society (e.g. healthcare, sustainable energy or building)

Skills -



Modelling, optimization, algorithms



Energy systems

Data Science

Java

GIT

Frontend



Languages

French

native speaker

English

bilingual

Spanish

intermediate

Swedish

German

intermediate

Hobbies



Climbing, rowing, karate

Wood work, plumbing, eco-building techniques

Bike touring

Work experience -



Project manager, developper - Artelys, Paris May 2016 - June 2022

Developement of numerical optimization code and heuristics, applied to energy systems, energy markets and logistics. Web experience: electrical network simulation tool (see link

Technos: Java/ Python/ Mosel/ AMPL/ Knitro/ Docker/ git / SQL/ Javascript/React/Node.JS/Webpack

PhD - EDF/CentraleSupélec

March 2013 - March 2016

Model Predictive Control and optimization of energy plants, based on 1st principle models. MATLAB, Modelica, JModelica

Internship - Mastère OSE - EDF R&D

March - September 2012

Modelica library for quick sizing energy plants

Internship-thermal engineering - TitanX, Sweden

February - August 2011

Migration of a heat exchanger computation software, and integration of new numerical methods for simulation and parameter fitting

Education



- DataScientist, Udacity
 - August 2022
- Front End Web Developper, Udacity

June - October 2020

Machine learning (Andrew Ng), Coursera June - October 2016

Post master specialization in energy system optimization, Mines Paristech

September 2011 - September 2012

Master degree of engineering, ESSTIN September 2006 - September 2011

Energy/Fluid mechanics/ Computer science and automatic control. One year as exchange student in Sweden

Baccalauréat Scientifique - Highest honors June 2006